four things i like about the force usa
walk through trap bar or that it has an
open design so you can walk right into
it it has a built-in jack that way it
makes it super easy to change your
plates you have two different handles
for you to grip onto during your
deadlifts and you also have a handle on
top that's gonna make it super easy to
move it around your home gym
but you can also use this for your
suitcase carries if you want to what's
up my people it's jake back with another
review in the barbin garage gym for
today i've got the force usa walk
through trap bar in this video i'm going
to take you through everything you need
to know about this bar from the price
the features some pros and cons and of
course who should or maybe should not
add this to their home gym but before we
get going here today i've got to let you
know we've reviewed a good amount of
trap bars on barbin.com and if you want
to browse our best list just go ahead
and search barbind best trap bars and
you can find out for yourself which ones
that we like the best
[Music]
okay so i'm gonna give you a little bit
more details now about what i like about
this trap bar let's start with the
design
i really like the fact that there's no
bar down here it's open you can walk
right through it there's nothing to step
over or worry about tripping over i
guess since it is open you know you can
definitely use this for walking lunges
if you want to i really like the fact
that it has a built-in jack it's
probably my favorite feature to be
honest with you all you have to do is
flip it up like i have it right now and
you can easily load or unload your
plates on either side super simple to do
the handle on top right here is going to
make it really easy to move it around
your gym if you want but you can also
use this for suitcase carries if you
want to and then you also have two
handles on either side of this trap bar
so that way you can switch up your grip
during your workouts if you want to
with that being said there are a couple
issues that i noticed that you might
also run into while you're working out
with this trap bar let's start with the
handles all right so i saw online some
people leaving reviews saying they
thought these handles were made of
plastic i don't think that's true i
definitely think they're made of some
type of metal i just don't know what
exactly that is and you do have knurling
right here but it's not cut very deep so
for somebody like myself i tend to kind
of struggle in getting you know a solid
grip throughout my entire workout with
this trap bar so in between sets i'm
often having to wipe my hands off and
dry them off that's just something to
think about the top handles right here
on either side they're about 31 inches
apart
that might be too wide for some people
to get a proper workout with this trap
bar and the loading sleeves are shorter
than what you're going to find on a
barbell so barbells typically have
loading sleeves of around 16 inches or
so
these are just under 13. so i think you
could run into the issue of running out
of space on either end of this trap bar
before you really come close to maxing
out the weight which is around 660
pounds also you know you do have to put
this together there's a lot of trap bars
out there that you don't have to
assemble maybe the loading sleeves but
with this i mean everything you see on
here i had to put together myself it
only took me around 20 to 30 minutes
wasn't that bad but something to think
about and it's not really cheap it's 400
now there are definitely cheaper trap
bars out there for you to purchase but
you know the added features right here i
think it justifies the price comparing
to other trap bars out there that
features some of the same qualities
you're actually getting a pretty good
deal right here
okay so let's talk about the moolah the
force usa walk through trap bar it's
priced right around 400
tack on your shipping and taxes you're
looking at about 450. now i know that
might seem like a lot of money for trap
bar and like i said there's definitely
cheaper ones out there for you to
purchase but those also have a more
basic design this is pretty unique you
know it does have that built-in jack
which i personally love you do have the
handle right here it's gonna make it
pretty easy to move around your gym
as well as you know work in some
suitcase carry your workouts if you want
to and you also have two handles on
either side so it's gonna you know vary
the height of your grip during your
workouts so it's just pretty unique in
general with that being said i mean
there are other walk-through trap bars
you know available but those are either
more expensive than this one or they're
made of lesser quality which is you know
making them cheaper so
in the end i think you're getting a
pretty solid deal here because this is
such a unique piece of equipment you
also get a lifetime structural warranty
from any manufacturing defects and you
can even use a firm that way you can
split your purchase up into monthly
payments of around 35 or so so once
again i think this price is pretty
justified
[Music]
okay so i'm gonna walk y'all through all
the details of this trap barnell let's
start up top and start with this handle
right here i'm going to do this one
because all the other ones are identical
and you can see this one better now once
again i saw people online saying they
thought it was made of plastic i don't
think that's true it doesn't feel like
it it feels pretty solid to me i just
don't know what exactly it is made of
you do have a knurling right here it's
not very abrasive though so might not
give you that optimal grip that you're
looking for during your workouts and the
handles also spin all five of them spin
exactly the same
i didn't really notice anything
negatively during my workouts but you
know that could obviously
be different for you than it is for me i
have it standing upright on the built-in
jack right now i love that feature it's
probably my favorite one and because it
makes it super easy for me to load and
unload my plates but if i were to lay
this flat
there's this little padding right here
and that's gonna you know keep the trap
bar off the ground but also if you were
to drop this for whatever reason
this is going to take a good amount of
the impact as well as your bumper plates
as opposed to the framework of your trap
bar and it's going to add to the
durability of this piece of equipment
now when we go to the loading sleeves
here they're just under 13 inches so
compare that to the barbell a barbell
has loading sleeves of about 16 inches
so obviously you have some more room to
work with for the barbell than you do
here so technically you could run out of
spacing on the loading sleeves with your
bumper plates and that could be an issue
for some people who's lifting you know
super heavy weight
but you can still put a lot of heavy
weight on here at the same time now the
loading sleeves do not have any type of
grooves in them so that could be a cause
for concern for some people
you know because you do have a higher
chance of your weight plates scooting
down the loading sleeves but thankfully
your purchase does come with some grips
right here so
just going to clamp on and really just
keep those plates in their original
placement i really like the black matte
black coating of this trap bar just
brings a nice personal aesthetic that i
like myself and remember i had to put
this together myself only took me about
maybe 30 minutes or so but there are a
lot of little pieces here so keep that
in mind go ahead and set aside 30
minutes at least in your brain before
you start wanting to work out with this
bad boy
okay so who should purchase the force
usa walk through trap bar well if you
deadlift a lot maybe you're brand new to
dead lifting
i think you're gonna think that this is
a little bit easier to properly deadlift
because you have handles on either side
of you as opposed to you know using a
barbell and you have to reach out in
front of you it feels more natural in my
opinion and i think that actually in
turn can make it a little bit easier but
you know if you're not just wanting to
deadlift i think you'll really like the
versatility of this trap bar since you
can use it for farmers walks you know a
suitcase carry like i mentioned you can
do walking lunges maybe even different
shoulder workouts so that's a really
nice touch
and the design really might just be the
biggest selling point for this trap bar
in my opinion the built-in jack is
awesome it makes it super easy to load
and unload your weighted plates the
handle on top makes it also really easy
to store and move it around in your home
gym and because it is an open trap bar
it's a walk through you know in the name
it's a walk through trap bar
it just makes it super easy to step into
it okay so who should not purchase this
trap bar well
since the loading sleeves are just under
13 inches
if you only have bumper plates at home
you know which i would definitely
recommend that's what you use with this
trap bar in case you were to drop it for
whatever reason those are going to
protect essentially everything that's
involved but you know bumper plates tend
to be a little bit thicker than a
traditional weight plate so
since these are under 13 inches and once
again the barbell loading sleeves are
around 16 inches
i think you might run into the problem
where you run out of room on either
loading sleeve
before you really come close to that max
weight of around 660 pounds so that's
something to think about and you know
this is really targeted for deadlifting
i guess you could say so
when you're dead lifting you tend to be
you know lifting a lot of heavy weight
and you know since the handles do have
knurling but they're not cut very deep
so you really might not get that optimal
grip when you're going to lift and that
obviously could be a problem
you know around 450 bucks for this trap
bar is a pretty good deal since you do
have these you know added qualities and
features
but that's still not necessarily cheap
now
it is a little more affordable than some
other trap bars that are of similar
quality as this one but
if it falls out of your price range you
know there's definitely cheaper ones out
there for you to purchase
i just you know to be honest with you i
just don't know how long those are going
to last and this really does seem like
it's gonna last
me specifically a pretty long time
[Music]
all right well that's a wrap on today's
review over the force usa walk through
trap bar i personally love the design
here i love the built-in jack it makes
it super easy for me to load and unload
my weight plates and plus you have five
different handles right here so there's
a lot of added versatility to this trap
bar now i personally think this could be
a great addition really to anybody's
home gym but remember the knurling on
the handles right here are not very
abrasive so it might not give you that
ideal grip that you're looking for and
if you are somebody who deadlifts a lot
of heavy weight
you could run into the issue of running
out of space on either loading sleeve
before you get close to the 660 pound
threshold of this trap bar but with that
being said i still think you can load
some really heavy weight
onto this trap bar thanks for watching
everybody i hope this video was pretty
helpful and i hope that i answered some
questions that you might have over this
trap bar
i always say it i'm going to say it
again stay on the lookout for my next
video
but for now head over to barbin.com and
you can read more on this product just
search rbin force usa
walk through trap bar review and you can
read over everything we discussed here
today i'll see y'all next time
[Applause]
[Music]
you